Warren S. McCulloch Papers 1860s-1987 Mss.B.M139
American Philosophical Society
- Series III. Works by Warren S. McCulloch, 1921-1982; 4.25 lin. feet (Box 62-70)
  - "The Knee-jerk Following Facilitating and Extinguishing Stimulation of Related Cortical Foci", 1939; 3 items; J.G. Dusser de Barenne
    Lecture, Toronto meeting, 1939
  - "Kritisches und Experimentelles zur Deutung Potentialschwankungen des Elektrocorticogramms", 1938; 1 item; J.G. Dusser de Barenne
  - ["Lawrence Kubie"], n.d.; 1 item
  - "LEKTON", [1967]; 4 items
    Introduction to "The Logical Structure of Mind" by Eilhard von Domarus, a section from the monograph, Communication: Theory and Research, compiled and edited by Lee Thayer. See also [On the Circuit Theory of Brains]
  - "The Limiting Information Capacity of a Neuronal Link", 1951-1952; 5 items; Donald M. MacKay
    Printed in Bulletin of Mathematical Biophysics 1952
  - "Limits on Nerve Impulse Transmission", 1955; 1 item; P. D. Wall, J. y. Lettvin, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Living Models for Lively Artifacts", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Local Effects of Epinephrine on Cerebral Cortex", 1952-1953; 31 items; Bruno Minz and Antoine G. Remond
  - "Local Stimulatory Inactivation Within the Cerebral Cortex, the Fator for Extinction", 1937; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "A Logical Calculus of the Ideas Immanent in Nervous Activity", 1943; 1 item; Walter Pitts
  - "Logic and Closed Loops for a Computer Junket to Mars", 1967; 1 item
  - "Logisticon", 1960; 4 items
  - "Long Association Fibers in Cerebral Hemispheres of Monkey and Chimpanzee, 1943; 1 item; Percival Bailey, Gerhardt von Bonnin, Edward Davis, Hugh W. Garol, Ephraim Roseman, and Anibal Silveira
  - "Machines That Think and Want", 1947; 1 item; McCulloch, Warren S. (Warren Sturgis), b. 1898
  - "Maps Derived by Bipolar Microelectrode Stimulation Within the Spinal Cord", 1954; 1 item; P. D. Wall, J. Y. Lettvin, B. Howland, and W. H. Pitts
  - "The Measurment of Cortical Redox Potentials in Vivo", n.d.; 2 items; J. R, Kelin and A. Wikler
  - "Mechanisms for the Spread of Epileptic Activation of the Brain", 1949; 1 item
  - "Membrane Currents in Clamped Vertebrate Nerve", 1957; 1 item; Jose Del Castillo J. Y. Lettvin and W. Pitts
  - "Metaphysical Concepts", n.d.; 1 item
    Draft in a notebook. Also contains a draft of a paper explaining axonology
  - "A Model of the Vertebrate Central Command System, 1969; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer and J. Blum.
  - "The Modern Concept of Schizophrenia", 1944-1945; 14 items; L. J. Meduna
  - "Modes of Functional Organization of the Cerebral Cortex", 1947; 2 items
    Printed in Federation Proceedings 1947
  - "Morphine and the Central Nervous System", 1 item; A. E. Wikler, E. Davis, and C. Goodwin
  - "The 'Motor' Cortex of the Chimpanzee", 1941; 1 item; J.G. Dusser de Barenne and Hugh W. Carol
  - "Motor Response to Stimulation of Cerebral Cortex in Absence of Areas 4 and 6 (Macaca Mulatta), 1943; 1 item; Margaret Kennard
  - "Mysterium Iniquitatis of Sinful Man Aspiring into the Place of God", 1954-1955; 4 items
    Printed in Scientific Monthly 1954
  - "The Nature and Origin of Prolonged Events in the Terminal Arborizations of Spinal Afferent Fibers", 1956; 1 item; P. D. Wall, J. y. Lettvin, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Neurological Models and Integrative Processes", 1962; 5 items; Michale A. Arbib and Jack D. Cowan
  - "Neurophysiology I", n.d.; 1 item
  - "The Nervous System in Education", 1969; 1 item
  - "A New Method for the Investigation of the Electrical Properties of Living Tissue", 1935; 2 items; C. T. Lane and C.H. Prescott
  - "Norbert Wiener and the Art of Theory", 1965; 1 item
  - "Observations on the pH of the ARterial Blood, the pH and the Electrical Activity of the Cerebral Cortex", 1938; 1 item; J.G. Dusser de Barenne, Clyde S. Marshall, and Leslie F. Nims
  - "Of Digital Computers Called Brains", 1949; 19 items; John Pfeiffer
    Printed in Scientific Monthly 1949
  - "Of Digital Oscillators", 1969; 3 items
    Includes reprint from Information Processing in the Nervous System edited by K. N. Leibovic
  - "Of I and It", 1969; 4 items
    Printed in Perspectives in Biology and Medicine 1969
  - "Of Minding and Mattering", 1969; 6 items
  - "On a Cybernetic Theory of the Reticular Formation", n.d.; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer, J. Blum, E. Craighill, and D. Peterson
  - "One Component of the Extrapyramidal System", 1949; 10 items; A. A. Ward, Jr. and H.W. Magoun
    Lecture, Boston, 1949. Includes photographs of diagrams for published article
  - "One Word After Another", 1945; 2 items
  - "On Half the Extrapyramidal System", [1940's]; 2 items
  - "On Microelectrodes for Plotting Currents in Nervous Tissue.", 1953; 2 items; W. Pitts, B. Howland, J.Y. Lettvin, and P.D. Wall
  - "On Parallel Computation." Neurophysiology - Q.P.R., 1959; 1 item; Manuel Blum
  - "On Pathology and Memory", 1962; 2 items
    Conference on memory, Austin, TX
  - "On Probabilistic Logic", 1957; 6 items
  - [On the Circuit Theory of Brains], n.d.; 8 items
    Lecture. Contains original draft of McCulloch's cartoon of pointing man, dog, and rabbit. See also LEKTON
  - "On the Nature and Distribution of Factors for Facilitation and Extinction in the Central Nervous System", 1937; 1 item
    Lecture, American Phys. Society meeting, 1937
  - "Opening Remarks", n.d.; 1 item
  - "The Organizing Principle of Complex Living Systems", 1969; item; A. S. Iberall
  - "Parasympathetic Regulations of High Potentials in the Electroencephalogram", 1944; 2 items; Chester W. Darrow, John R. Green, Edward W. Davis, and Hugh W. Garol
  - "The Past of a Delusion", 1952; 2 folders
    Lecture, Chicago Literary Club, 1952
  - "pH of the Cerebral Cortex and Arterial Blood Under Insulin", 1939; 1 item; Clyde Marshall and Leslie F. Nims
  - "A Photokymographic Method with Continuous Cathode Ray Oscilograms", 1936; 1 item; G. R. Wendt
  - "Physical Treatments of Mental Diseases", 1953; 3 items
    Lecture, Edinburgh (BBC)
  - "Physiological Delimitation of Neurones in the Central Nervous System", 1939; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Physiological Neuronography of Some Cortico-Subcortical Connections in the Chimpanzee", 1944; 4 items; H. W. Garol
    Printed in Neurophysiology 1944
  - "Physiological Neuronography of the Cortico-Straital Connections", 1941; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne and Hugh W. Garol
  - "Physiological Processes Underlying Psychoneuroses", 1950; 16 items
  - The Physiology of Knowledge, 1959; 1 item
  - "Physiology of Thinking and Perception", 1954; 1 item
    Lecture, Creative Engineering
  - Preface to A Gordon Pask's An Approach to Cybernetics", 1961; 1 item
  - "A Preference for Related Areas, [1924-1929]; 1 item
    Early work at Columbia University
  - "The Problem of Localization in Experimentally Induced Convulsions", 1930; 1 item; F. H. Pike, C. A. Elsberg, and M. N. Chapell
  - "Production of an Alternating Tremor at Rest in the Monkey", 1948; 1 item; A. A. Ward, Jr. and H.W. Magoun
  - "The Production of Postural Tremor", 1949; 2 items; Eric W. Peterson, H.W. Magoun, and Donald B. Lindsley
  - "Progress Report on Synaptic Transmission", 1953-1954; 1 item; P.D. Wall, W.H. Pitts, B. Howland, and J.Y. Lettvin.
  - "The Projection of Area 19 to the Reticular Formation", 1948; 1 item; Elwood Henneman
  - "The Projection of the Frontal Lobe on the Hypothalmus", 1947; 1 item; Arthur A. Ward, Jr.
  - "Ragna Rökr", 1968; 5 items
  - "Rapid Changes in Cerebral Oxygen Tension Induced by Altering the Oxygenation and Circulation of the Blood", 1945; 3 items; Ephraim Roseman and Craig W. Goodwin
  - "Rapid Changes in the O2 Tension of Cerebral Cortex During Convulsions", 1944; 1 item; E. Roseman and E. W. Davis
  - "A Recapitulation of the Theory, with a Forecast of Several Extensions", 1948; 1 item
  - "Recent Trends in the Electroencephalogram", 1941; 1 item
    Lecture, Neurology-Psychiatry Symposium, 1941
  - "Recollections of the Many Sources of Cybernetics", 1974; 1 item
  - "Regenerative Loop", 1968-1969; 8 items
    Printed in Journal of Nervous and Mental Disease 1969
  - "Relation of Cortex to Basal Ganglia", 1942; 4 items
    Lecture, Chicago Neurological Society, 1942
  - "The Reliability of Biological Systems", 1959; 11 items
    Printed in Proceedings of the Interdisciplinary Conference on Self-Organizing Systems 1959
  - "Reliable Systems Using Unreliable Units", 1962-1964; 2 items
  - "Reflex Inhibition by Dorsal Root Interaction", 1954; 1 item; B. Howland, B., J. Y. Lettvin, W. Pitts, and P. D. Wall
  - "Repetitive Movements on Basal Ganglia Stimulation after Transection of Cerebral Peduncles", 1947; 1 item; W. H. Sweet and R. S. Snider
  - "The Reticular Formation: Part I Modeling Studies of the Reticular Formation", 1969; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer and J. Blum.
  - "The Reticular Formation: Part II The Biology of the Reticular Formation", 1969; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer and J. Blum.
  - "The Reticular Formation Command and Control System", 1969; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer
    Reprint from Information Processing in the Nervous System edited by K. N. Leibovic
  - "Santiago Ramon y Cajal (1852-1934) and His Investigation of the Nervous System", 1953; 1 item; S. Polyak
  - "Sensorimotor Cortex, Nucleus Caudatus and Thalmus Opticus", 1938; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Sensory Cortex of Chimpanzee." 1940, 1 item; Percival Bailey, Hugh W. Garol, and J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "The Sensory Cortex of the Chimpanzee." 1939, 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Sensory Cortex of Chimpanzee." 1940, 1 item; Percival Bailey, Hugh W. Garol, and J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Signes Electriques Des Evenements Eloignes Dans le Systeme Nerveux Central", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Site of Action of Indole in the Central Nervous System", 1944; 1 item; I. M. Feinberg
  - "Somatic Functions of the Central Nervous System", 1948; 1 item; Jerome Y. Lettvin
  - "Some Connections of the Frontal Lobe Established by Physiological Neuronography", 1947; 1 item
  - "Some Effects of Laminar Thermocoagulation Upon the Local Action Potentials of the Cerebral Cortex of the Monkey", 1936; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Some Effects of Local Strychninization on Action Potentials of the Cerebral Cortex of the Monkey, 1936; 1 item; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "Some Mechanisms for a Theory of the Reticular Formation", 1968; 1 item; W. L. Kilmer and J. Blum.
  - "Some New Techniques for the Electrophysiological Study of the Central Nervous System", 1953; 4 items
    Lecture, University College, London, 1953
  - "Some Observations on Experimentally Produced Convulsions", 1930; 1 item; F. H. Pike, C.A. Elsberg, and M.N. Chapell.
  - "Some Remarks on What is New with Us", 1967; 3 items
    Lecture, Symposium on the Engineering Significance of the Biological Sciences, 1967
  - "Some Suggestions for a Quantitative Approach to Problems in Psychiatry, Introduction to", 1942; 1 item
    Lecture, Seminar on Psychosomatic Medicine, 1942
  - "Stability of Biological Systems", 1957; 2 items
    Printed in IRE Transactions 1957
  - "A Statistical Consequence of the Logical Calculus of Nervous Nets", 1943; 2 items; H. D. Landahl and Walter Pitts
    Printed in Bulletin of Mathematical Biophysics 1943
  - "The Statistical Organization of Nervous Activity", 1948; 2 items; Walter Pitts
  - "Studies in Carbohydrate Metabolism and Its Regulation in Health and Disease in the Central Nervous System", 1963-1964; 12 items
    Lecture, New York Academy of Sciences, 1963
  - "Studies in Carbohydrate Metabolism and Its Regulation in Health and Disease in the Central Nervous System" (Abstract), 1 item
  - "Summary of the Action of Strychnine", 1958; 2 items
  - "Summary of the Points of Agreement Reached in the 9th Conference on Cybernetics", 1952; 3 items
  - "Summary of Theory and Extension to Gestalt Psychology", 1946; 1 item
    Lecture, Conference on Teleological Mechanisms, 1946
  - "Summary of Work, 1955", 1 item; Jerome Y. Lettvin, W.H. Pitts, and P.D. Wall
  - "Summary Report of Seminar on Computation in the Presence of Noise", 1961; 1 item; J. D. Cowan
  - "Sundry Changes in Physiology of Cerebral Cortex Following Rapid Injectin of Sodium Cyanide", 1947; 1 item; Max D. Wheatley
  - "Superfluity of Naughtiness", 1969; 3 items
    Lecture, Burg Wartenstein Symposium
  - "Suppression of Motor Response Upon Stimulation of Area 4-s of the Cerebral Cortex", 1939; 2 items; J. G. Dusser de Barenne
  - "A Suppressor Cerebello-Bulbo-Reticular Pathway from Anterior Lobe and Paramedian Lobules", 1947; 1 item; R. S. Snider and H. W. Magoun
  - "Symbolic Representation of the Neuron as an Unreliable Function", 1961; 1 item
  - "Symposium: The Design of Machines to Simulate the Behavior of the Human Brain", 1956; 1 item
  - "The Synthesis of Reliable Systems from Less Reliable Components", 1962; 2 items
  - Talk, n.d.; 2 items
  - Talk given at the interurban medical meeting, n.d.; 1 item
  - Talk at the Instumentation Laboratory, 1966; 1 item
  - Talk at the Instumentation Laboratory, 1966; 2 items
  - Talk given at the Memphis meeting, n.d.; 2 items
  - Talk given at "Symposium on Computer Users", 1966; 2 items
  - Talk given at the Toronto Meeting, n.d.; 1 item
    American Physical Society?
  - Talk given at the Washington meeting of the American Physical Society, n.d.; 1 item
  - Talks Given, 1958-1961, 4 items
    Lists of talks
  - "Temporal and Spatial Distribution of Changes During Spontaneous Seizures in Monkey Brain", 1948; 8 items; A. A. Ward and N. Kopeloff
  - "A Theory of Passive Ion Flux through Axon Membranes", 1964; 1 item; J. Y. Lettvin, W. F. Pickard, and W. Pitts
  - "The Terminal Arborisation of the Cat's Pyramidal Tract Determined by a New Technique", 1955/6; 1 item; P. D. Wall, J. y. Lettvin, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Through the Den of the Metaphysician", 1948-1950; 4 items
    Lecture, University of Virginia, with later comments on the manuscript in a long letter by F. S. C. Northrop
  - "Toward some Circutry of Ethical Robots", 1952-1956; 2 folders
  - "Towards a Theory of the Reticular Formation", 1964; 2 items; W. L. Kilmer
  - Transcript of a taped lecture, n.d.; 1 item
  - Unidentified, 1949; 1 item
    Reprint from Electrical Engineering. Not by McCulloch?
  - Untitled discussion, n.d.; 1 item
    Printed discussion includes Charles Moore and Steven Coons
  - Untitled lecture at Barth Foundation, 1960; 1 item
  - Unitled, 1965; 4 items
    Paper on the reticular system from the IFIP Meeting. Contains handwritten draft
  - Unitled, 1969-1982; 4 items
    Paper on neurophsychaitry with Juan de Dios Pozo-Olano. Contains a later letter to Rook McCulloch
  - Untitled talk, 1962; 1 item
    Talk
  - Unitled transcription, 1942; 3 items
    Transcription of a discussion at the American Neuroligical Association
  - "Uses of Strychnine", 1964; 3 items
  - "The Utility of Anastomotic Nets", 1962; 1 item
  - "What EEG Can Never Show", 1953; 13 items
  - "What Is a Number, That a Man May Know It, and a Man, That He May Know a Number?", 1960; 4 items
    Ninth Annual Alfred Korzybski Memorial Lecture
  - "What's in the Brain that Ink May Character?", 1964; 4 items
    Lecture, International Congress for Logic, Methodology and Philosophy of Science
  - "What's New to Speak, What New to Register", 1964; 4 items
  - "What the Frog's Eye Tells the Frog's Brain", 1959; 1 item; J. Y. Lettvin, H. R. Maturana, and W. H. Pitts
  - "Wheel in a Wheel", 1967; 3 items
  - "Where is Fancy Bred?", n.d.; 1 item
  - "Why the Mind is in the Head", 1951; 2 items
  - Zest and Carbo-Hydrate Metabolism, 1950; 1 item; Helen B. Carlson and Franz G. Alexander
- Series IV. Works by others, 1937-1979; 4.0 lin. feet (Box 70-78)
  Works of McCulloch's colleagues and others. Some correspondence and early drafts are included.
  - "Dyslexia: A Discussion of Its Definition", 1967; 1 item; Adams, Richard B
  - "Colliculospinal Paths", 1954; 1 item; Andrew, Alexander M
  - [Papers], 1967; 6 items; Andrew, Alexander M
  - Research proposal, 1964; 1 item; Andrew, Alexander M
  - "Automata Theory and the Central Nervous System", ca. 1968; 1 item; Arbib, Michael A
  - "Hitting and Martingale Characterizations of One-Dimensional Diffusions", 1964; 1 item; Arbib, Michael A
  - "How We Know Universals: Retrospect and Prospect", 1970; 1 item; Arbib, Michael A
  - "Logical Calculus", 1962-1963; 4 items; Arbib, Michael A
    Contains offprint, and correspondence
  - "Partial Survey of Cybernetics Eastern Europe and Soviet Union", 1964; 1 item; Arbib, Michael A
  - "Simple Self-Reproducing Universal Automata", n.d.; 1 item; Arbib, Michael A
  - "Computer Program for Simulation of Perceptrons and Similar Neural Networks", 1966; 1 item; Barker, T.H
  - "Art of the South Seas", 1946; 1 item; Bateson, Gregory, 1904-1980
  - "From One Social Scientist to Another", 1946; 1 item; Bateson, Gregory, 1904-1980
  - "Physical Thinking and Social Problems", 1946; 1 item; Bateson, Gregory, 1904-1980
  - "Of Dance and Song", 1969; 1 item; Bateson, Mary Catherine
  - "The Study of Cultural Patterns in European Nations", 1946; 1 item; Benedict, Ruth, 1887-1848
  - "Model for the Generation of Electroencephalogram Alpha Rhythm Patterns", 1968; 2 items; Bess, Leon
  - "Cybernetics and Statistical Concepts of Entropy...", 1965; 2 items; Biser, Ervin
    Full title: "Cybernetics and Statistical Concepts of Entropy and Correlation Relating to Systems Analysis and Sythesis (Partitions of Discrete Information Spaces"
  - "Properties of a Neuron with Many Inputs", 1960; 1 item; Blum, Manuel
  - "Notice complementaire... du Dr. Georges Bourguignon", 1937; 1 item; Bourguignon, Georges
    Full title "Notice complementaire des exposes de 1931 et 1937 sur les titres et travaux du Dr. Georges Bourguignon"
  - "On the Dynamics of Narcissim", 1965; 2 items; Brodey, Warren M
  - "On Excitatory and Inhibitory Processes within the Motor Centers of the Brain", 1 item; Bubnoff, N. and R. Heidenhain
    Translated by McCulloch and Bonin
  - "Mechanization of Thought and Language Processes", 1965; 1 item; Ceccato, Silvio
  - "Non-Linear Systems", 1956-1968; 2 items; Clauser, Francis H
    Printed in Journal of the Aeronautical Sciences 1956
  - First Thoughts Toward a Thesis, 1961; 1 item; Colby, R.H
  - "Conference on Redundancy Techniques in Computing Systems", 1962; 1 item; Cowan, J. D
    In Washington, D.C.
  - "Some Remarks on Channel Bandwidths for Visual Contrast Detection", 1 item; Cowan, J. D
  - "A statistical Mechanics of Nervous Activity", [1969]; 1 item; Cowan, J. D
  - "Automatic Speech Recognition Based on a New Segmentation Procedure", n.d.; 1 item; Craighill, E. and W. Kilmer
  - Miscellany #1, n.d.; 1 item; Craik, Kenneth James Williams
  - Miscellany #2, n.d.; 1 item; Craik, Kenneth James Williams
  - Miscellany #3, n.d.; 1 item; Craik, Kenneth James Williams
  - "Parasympathetic Regulations of High Potentials in the Electroencephalogram", 1944; 1 item; Darrow, Chester W., John R. Green, Edward W. Davis, and Hugh W. Garol
  - "Computational and Model-Derived Heuristics for Resolution of Logical Scheduling Conflicts", 1967; 1 item; Driscoll, Leo
  - "Computerized Contingency Analysis", 1968; 1 item; Driscoll, Leo
  - "Critical Race Problem in Multi-Processing", 1967; 1 item; Driscoll, Leo
  - "Pattern of Genetic Control of STructure in the Evolution of Behavior", 1967; 1 item; Du Brul, E. Lloyd
  - "Biomechanics of the Body", 1965; 1 item; Du Brul, E. Lloyd
  - "The Sensory Cortex of the Chimpanzee's Brain" (Review), 1939; 1 item; Dusser De Barenne, J. G
  - "Interrelations between Perception Adaptation Levels and Value", 1967; 2 items; Edwards, Robert F
  - "Evoked Potentials, Neural Efficiency, and IQ", 1 item; Ertl, J
  - "Computer Simulation of Biological Evolution", 1968; 3 items; Ewin, James C
  - "Reticulocortical Relations and the Problem of 'Central Integration'", 1961; 1 item; Fair, C. and A. E. Bennett
  - "A Calculus of N-adic relations", 1968-1969; 2 folders; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Analysis of Some Concepts in Psychopathology from the Viewpoint of Command and Control", 1972; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Attempt of a Operational Formulation of the Dynamics of Social Intervention", 1972; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Auto-and Cross-Correlation in Nets of Neuromimes", 1968; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "How and Why Do Paranoid Schizophrenic Patients Fail in a Simple Adaptive Task", 1973; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Information Retrieval in Neuronal Nets", 1968; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "LEKTON: A Commentary by Fonseca, J. Simoes da", n.d.; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Psychological Ecology from the Viewpoint of Signification and Intention", 1972; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Representation of the Behavior of Non-Linear Neural Nets...", 1967; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "What Is the Purpose" of Delay in Nets of Real Neurons?, 1967; 1 item; Fonseca, J. Simoes da
  - "Artificial Intelligence a la Russe", 1967; 1 item; Ford, J. J
  - "New Opportunities for the Improvement of Mental Hospitals", 1946; 1 item; Fremont-Smith, F
  - "The Motor Analysor", 1963; 1 item; Gambaryan, L. S
  - "Bionics and Related Research", 1963; 1 item; Gibbs, Katye M
  - "Adaptive Approach to Soothing, Filtering, and Prediction", 1969; 1 item; Gilstrap, Lewey O
  - "A 'Fourth Branch' of Government", 1963; 1 item; Golovin, N. E
  - "Reflections on the AIAA/ORSA Forum on Systems Analysis and Social Change", 1968; 1 item; Golovin, N. E
  - A Basic Model of Cognition, n.d.; 1 item; Goodall, M. C
  - "Brain-Wave 'Correlator'", 1948; 1 item; Goodwin, A
  - "Style of the Brain", n.d.; 1 item; Greene, Peter
  - "Cybernetics and the Transition from Classical to Trans-Classical Logic", 1 item; Gunther, Gotthard
  - "Information, Communication and Many-Valued Logic", 1 item; Gunther, Gotthard
  - "Natural Numbers in Transclassic Systems", 1969; 2 items; Gunther, Gotthard
  - "Time, Timeless Logic and Self-Referential Rystems", 1 item; Gunther, Gotthard
  - "Do Random Logic Nets Provide Key to Genetic Control?", 1968; 2 items; "H. L. D."
  - "The Scatterings of Polarized Light by Polydisperse Systems of Irregular Particles", n.d.; 1 item; Holland, Alfred C
  - "On Nature, Life, Mind and Society: Fragments of a Vigorous Systems' Science, 1976; 1 item; Iberall, A[thur] S
  - Authors, B-G, 1939; 9 items; International Congress for the Unity of Science
    Papers distributed at the ICUS meeting of 1939 that were to be included in The Journal of Unified Science (Erkenntnis), vol. IX
  - Authors, K-P, 1939; 6 items; International Congress for the Unity of Science
  - Authors, Q-W, 1939; 10 items; International Congress for the Unity of Science
  - "In Search of Homunculus", 1968; 1 item; Jacobi, George T
  - "Two Combinatorial Problems About Cycles", 1965; 4 items; Isaacs, Rufus
  - "Is This Machine Intelligent?", 1967; 1 item; Johnson, A. R
  - "Servo-Analysis of Postural Reflexes", 1959; 1 item; Johnson, A. R
  - "Notes on Social Forecasting", 1966; 1 item; Jouvenal, Bertrand de
  - "Taking the Fear Out of Math", 1978; 1 item; Kamin, Ira
    Article on woman mathematician Lenore Blum
  - "Metabolic Stability and Epigenesis in Randomly Constructed Genetic Nets", 1968; 1 item; Kauffman, S. A
  - "An Experimental Analysis of the Functions of the Basal Ganglia", n.d.; 1 item; Kennard, M. A
  - "Temporal Reversal of Land Effect Color Rules", 1 item; Kilmer, Ellen and W. Kilmer
  - "AFOSR Proposal for 1969 4 Figures Attached", 1 item; Kilmer, [William]
  - "The Biology of the Reticular Formation", 1969; 1 item; Kilmer, William L
  - Diagram, and letter exchange with James W. Woods about decerebrating cats, 1968; 3 items; Kilmer, William L
  - "An Iterated Net Model of the Vertebrate Command and Control System", 1965-1966; 2 items; Kilmer, William L
  - "On Dynamic Switching in One-Dimensional Iterative Logic Networks", 1963; 1 item; Kilmer, William L